# Akolade Ojesina

### ojeshinaakolade@gmail.com

## **Summary**

Passionate and motivated postgraduate student with over 2 years' experience writing Python. Looking for an opportunity to work in a challenging position combining my skills in Data Science and Software engineering, which provides professional development, interesting experiences and personal growth.

## **Experience**

### **Python/Django Developer**, **Freelance**, 6/2020 - Present

Built several web based applications (Blogs, Customer Management System) using Django framework, HTML, CSS and JavaScript. My responsibilities include researching, planning and managing projects, designing the feature, creating wireframes, and writing out specifications.

### **Data Science, Freelance** 12/2019 - Present

- Completed analysis on different datasets to generate insights and business intelligence.
- Used various models and libraries such as Numpy, Pandas, Scikit-Learn etc.

### **Software Development Intern at Classic InfoTech, Nigeria.** 07/2019 – 6/2020

- Designed and developed the UI of websites using HTML, CSS and JavaScript.
- Created database using MySQL, wrote several queries to extract data from database.
- Worked with the team of architects and back-end Developers to gather requirements and enhance functionality.
- Contributed to technical design documentation.

## **Education**

University of Ibadan, Oyo State, Nigeria

Masters of Information Science, 2019 – Present

Adeyemi College of Education, Ondo State, Nigeria

B.Sc(Ed.) Physics, 2015

## **Technical Skills**

Experience in Product Management, Analytics/Statistics, and Software Engineering. Tools:

- Data Science: Python with NumPy, Pandas and Scikit Learn.
- Programming Technologies: SQL, Django, Java, JavaScript, HTML/CSS(Bootstrap)

# **Projects**

#### Customer Management System, October 2020

I built a customer management system with HTML, CSS and JavaScript on frontend and a functional database system integrated with Django MVC for a fashion designing company to track customer details, save measurements, monitor schedules and timeframe.

### Data Science Nigeria AI Bootcamp Hackathon, September 2020

I built a machine learning model for predicting customers who are likely to default or not for a retail company as part of the Data Science Nigeria AI Bootcamp qualification competition. This was done by ensembling models, utilizing Python libraries such as NumPy, Pandas and Matplotlib. I ranked at the 154<sup>th</sup> place out of 750 participants at the competition which was hosted on Zindi.